good afternoon, yes, look, I’m asking
добрый день да смотрите я спрашиваю
people from Russia how they feel about the fact
людей из россии как они относятся к тому
that Russia could start a nuclear war,
что россия может начать ядерную войну
I’ll say that
я так скажу что
I agree why,
я согласен зачем
that is, sense, that is, you support the fact
то есть смысле то есть вы поддержите то
that your government is ready somewhere for mysticism,
что ваша власть и готова где-то мистику
this is a nuclear strike on the other side
это ядерный удар по другой стороны
of course, because if we don’t
конечно потому что потому что если мы не
show nuclear weapons
показывать ядерное оружие
over time, we just
со временем нас просто
turn
повернуть
it around, it’s not entirely clear what they want to
не совсем понятно что хотят с вами
make
сделать
nuclear weapons with you for something as a deterrent
ядерное оружие для чего-то сдерживающий
so that we won’t be disturbed later by missiles
чтобы нас потом не тревожили ракеты
that we are far from us that
которые мы далеко от нас который
let’s
допустим
stand
стоять
, we’ll show gentlemen  from the European Union,
уже покажем господа из евросоюза
Mr.
господин
other citizens, and you yourself brought down the city, it’s
другие граждане а вы сами сбил города
just that the city is going through this gap and
просто этот пробел город переживает и
bending because
выгнуть потому что
you are in what part of Russia and
вы в какой части россии и
Western Siberia far to without it turns out
западной сибири далеко до без получается
I agree this is the most
я согласен это самый
[music] the
[музыка]
last one can be done, but you
последний можно сделать но можно
can and let them know that Russian
можно и пусть это знают что русский
he is patient and of course, but
человек он долготерпит и конечно но
guys, let me know Bismarck also
ребята так пускай знаю еще бисмарк
spoke German, I know thousands of ways
говорил немецкий я знаю тысячи способов
just  wake up to pull the bears of the Russian
как разбудить вытащить медведи русского
out of the den, but I don’t know a single one how to
из берлоги но ни одного не знаю как
shove it,
засунуть его
so you don’t have to anger Mr. Putin,
поэтому не надо злить господина путина а
but how to calculate from
вот как как высчитать из почему как бы
why America and the European Union want to seize
америка нато и евросоюз хотят захватить
Russia, it turns out
россию получается
because it’s
потому что
necessary,
нужно
therefore Ukraine uses it
поэтому украины используют
because it was so throws  but
потому что она была так то броски но
apparently she no longer considers me I don’t
судя по всему она уже не считает меня не
understand
понимаю
talking yes you [ __ ]
говорить да ты охренел
understand you
понятно вас
all the people we already have our own beliefs the
все люди у нас уже свои убеждения
complexity of America it was necessary but
сложности америке это нужно было но
America they are doing in America it’s not about
америке них дела в америке дело-то не в
America but in whom,
америке а в ком
in fact, the whole bunch is twisting  far from
ведь по сути всю кучу крутит далеко не
who but those who although they were used
имеет кто а те кто хотя их использовали
america always from kolonna hotel 11 who are
америка всегда от kolonna hotel 11 кто
britain britain
британии британия
because america is the country of the show this is the
потому что америка это страна шоу это
stage but for the scenes from
сцена но за сцены из
which they lead that is britain is
которой руководят то есть британия
correct according to the british queen is
правильно по британская королева
responsible for this all that is
ответственна за вот это все что сейчас
happening now so
происходит так
this  just a
это всего лишь
screen and who can name
ширма а кто фамилии вы можете назвать
personal surnames you understand who is twisting this
персональные себе понял кто крутит этим
all
всем
just the
просто
owners of the
владельцы
printing press
печатного станка
[music  yka]
[музыка]
3 stakes with this in the federal system of the
3 ставки с это в федеральной системе
river,
реки
here you started the form of ice, I’m interested in
вот вы начали форме льда мне интересно
personalities, too, some freemasons,
персоналий тоже какие-то масоны
reptilians, specific surnames, so not
рептилоиды конкретных фамилиях так не
figuratively, the dish,
образно блюдо я образно
figuratively, Russia Putin is clear there, but in
вот россия путин там понятно а в
Britain who is responsible Rothschilds who
британии кто ответствен ротшильды кто
else
еще
who else
кто еще
but if there are a lot  then call it
но если много то назовите это
I don’t know honestly for me this discovery
я не знаю честно для меня это открытие
became, I thought about it really,
стало я задумывался реально
that is, then it turns out that Britain through
то есть получается тогда британия через
its puppets of the European Union and America
своих марионеток евросоюза и америку
wants to capture Russia
хочет захватить россию
remember the history of World War 1
вспомните историю 1 мировой войны
from China China on which side is
от китая китай на чьей стороне
Russia for Britain and for whom
тот за россию за британию и за кого
so far
пока что
I won’t say that China and I are
я не буду говорить что мы с китаем
now
сейчас
no, of course, you’re a zombie fool,
нет конечно дура
but
зомбированный но
this is an ancient civilization,
это это древняя цивилизация а
but look, you live in Siberia
вот смотрите вот вы живете в сибири так
and say that Britain wants to capture you there,
и говорите что там британия хочет вас
but I see people in Britain
захватить но я смотришь люди в британии
live richer than people in Siberia really
живут богаче чем люди в сибири правда
why Britain  seizes
зачем британии захватывает себе
britain britain kanash gave its colonies
британия британия канаш колонии свои
there
отдала там
there of australia desires for andy
там of australia желания на энди
how
как
they here their a  American pawns to bring the
они сюда своих американских пешек чтобы
economy
экономики
here our best brains are students at I
сюда наши лучшие мозги студентов на я
honestly say 90 and
честно говорю 90 а
now we have risen from our knees so
сейчас мы поднялись с колен так
I won’t then Russia
я не буду то россии
[music]
[музыка]
garbage dump this
помойке это
good
хорошо например
how much do they earn as an
профессии они сколько зарабатывают
engineer in your city
инженер вас в вашем городе
yes but an engineer in america or an engineer in
да но инженер в америке или инженер в
britain
британии
gets more than an engineer in russia
получает побольше чем инженер в россии
why that's how smart people they run away from
почему вот как умные люди они убегают из
russia why they don't get that kind of
россии почему им не дают там такую
salary there for example
зарплату например
to the west because it's better there
на запад потому что там лучше
because  there, in general, it’s like,
потому что там вообще как бы а
why, why, why there is no progress in Russia,
из-за чего почему почему в россии нет
but in the West there is
прогресса а на западе есть
because Russia slowed down at what
потому что россия тормозилось в какое
time
время
it seems to me I don’t know
мне кажется не знаю
maybe
возможно
stagnation, but look, the fact is that if
застои но смотрите дело в том что если
we look at the Soviet Union, it’s even
мы смотрим советский союз так он даже к
like this whole  a powerful Soviet propaganda machine,
вот эта вся мощная советская машина с
it lost
пропагандой она проиграла
technological America and Europe, that is,
технологические америке и европе то есть
when they already had computers
когда у них были уже компьютеры в домах
in people's homes, it was wild for us  a novelty
у людей для нас это была диковинка
in general
вообще
what and when the path was left why they
что и когда осталось путь почему они
could about the
смогли о
fact that
том что
when the owner was gone,
когда не стало хозяин
look around and you didn’t think that the issue of
осмотрите а вы не думали что вопрос
industrialization is not Stalin’s merit,
индустриализации это не заслуга сталина
it’s just an era, for example, look,
это просто эпоха вот например смотрите у
you got the Internet in Russia, and
вас появился интернет в россии так вот
now it appeared to me because of -  for Yeltsin
сейчас он же появился мне из-за ельцина
and the lines launched it will appear because
и линии запустил появится потому что по
all over the world it began to appear so
всему миру начал появляться так
technology has reached the same
технологии дошли то так же само
industrialization itself is a process that
индустриализация это процесс который
took place in all countries, they
проходил во всех странах они только вот
just didn’t industrialize before Stalin’s
до сталина не было индустриализация
death became industrialization and
преставления стала индустриализации и
you can do it with yours under Putin and oh under
можно так с вашим при путине и ом при
Yeltsin  the internet appeared in ukra in russia
ельцине в [__] в россии появился
and it
интернет и
doesn’t work out and caught on
не имеют получается не и застали на
industrialization it was just a
индустриализацию было просто
certain hysterical process
определенный процесс истерический
going on
проходит
now if you were a curator that it wouldn’t
вот были бы вы куратор что не было бы не
give realization but
даст реализации а
[laughter]
[смех]
Stalin who was who he was by
сталин кто такой был кем он был по
education
образование
but who he was  by education was
но тем кем он по образованию был
well, what kind of education in the
ну какое образование
law is a seminary dative laptop
закона семинария датив ноуте
close, close, yes, tiflis, what is it
близко-близко это да тифлис как она
called  I was good at a psychologist, that is,
называлась на психолог хорош то есть
why is he a
почему он
theological seminarian could lead the
духовный семинарист смог бы руководить
side you would not be able to because
сторона вы бы не смогли потому что
Stalin
сталин
and plus he is a man, and
и плюс он человек а
this is very good, but
это очень но хорошо
look how many people and Ukrainians and
посмотрите сколько людей и украинцев и
Russians and other peoples killed, in fact,
русских и других народов убил по сути
Stalin was
сталину
repressed to the pier, that is, it
репрессированные до пристани то есть
turns out  that in Europe all these buildings
получается что в европе все эти здания
were built by ordinary people for a salary and they
строили обычные люди за зарплату так и
built it, but in the USSR in the soup, did
построили а в ссср в супе разве там
people have to regress in order for
приходилось регрессировать людей чтобы
them to build it
они его строили здание
? The building is not a very
я не совсем
specific story, but I know that in the
конкретную историю но я знаю что на
West they
западе у
have a
них
financial part, they are very
финансовая часть они ведь очень
pragmatic with extra accents
прагматичный лишним акцентами ему и его
you won’t throw him and him you look when you
не кинете вы смотрите вы когда вы
come when you go to the store there why
приходите когда в магазин там почему
potatoes, for example, so many rubles
картошка например столько рублей
take a thread more extra rubles
возьмите нить еще дополнительные рубли
you won’t throw an extra ruble really why
вы лишнего рубля не кинете правда почему
they should feed an extra ruble
они должны питать лишнего рубля
well you look imagine from you
хорошо вы смотрите представьте от вы
now a loader you work for your family
сейчас грузчик вы работаете у вас семья
you get for the light not ah well well
вы получаете за свет не а ну ну хорошо
yourself i.e. you get money so i
самим то есть вы получаете деньги так я
yourself and you honestly earned them, but
себя и вы честно их заработали а
imagine now, for example, the path of
представляете сейчас у например путь
Ingrid, oh, let me be, how Stalin
ингрид о давайте я буду как сталин
took you for some reason, you and the
забрал вас по каких-то там вот вы с
Ukrainians talked at roulette, so
украинцам разговаривали в рулетке так
everyone, let’s repress him now and
все давайте его сейчас репрессирует и
now you will ship the same thing, but
теперь вы тоже самое грузите но
for free, so for what  -something is singing
бесплатно так за какой-то поет где-то
somewhere on the Belomor Canal and
там на беломор канале и
then you would have your grandchildren
вы бы потом вот ваши ваши внуки
tell Putin was good under
рассказывали вот путин был хорошим при
him they built something
нем построили там что-то
about Stalin’s justification,
про оправдание сталина
I’m
я
someone not only an inflection, but the genocide of people
кто не то что перегиба то геноцид людей
was so many millions of people destroyed
было столько миллионам людей уничтожили
so many Russians and  Ukrainians were not
столько русских и украинцев не
destroyed how many
уничтожили сколько
all the same, this period
все таки вот этот период
we began to lose the union in the
мы союз начали терять
seventies, first because of which
семидесятых сначала из-за чего
the enemy began to be isolated by the West,
началось изолирование западом противник
stagnation, these, again, these
застой вот эти опять же вот эти
bureaucratic upwards, why did the
бюрократические вверх почему уезжали
scientist
ученый
leave Russia, then because
из россии потом потому что
let's say a
допустим
person created
человек создал
what object in order for him
какой предмет для того чтобы он
moved the
продвинул
papers to draw up permission
бумаг составить разрешение
there to go here here here here and in the
туда сходить сюда сюда сюда сюда и в
end get nothing but in the west everything is
итоге получить ничего а на западе все к
about  rushed around quickly saw a person with such people to
этому относились быстро видел человека с
find out why because to look
узнать почему потому что смотреть потому
because in the west there was a market economy
что на западе было рыночная экономика
so if you are an inventor you have
так если ты изобретатель у тебя все
done everything patent the company came everything took the
сделал патент фирма пришло все взяла у
right to a patent from you there you
тебя там право на патент реализовала ты
got a lot of money you became a wealthy
получил кучу денег ты стал обеспеченным
person out of your mind and  then all and in the
человеком из своим умом а то вся а в
Soviet Union you can
советском союзе ты максимумах
count on the maximum for apartments there, a point behind
рассчитывать на там квартир очку отстали
on a one-room apartment, for example
на однокомнатную например
[music]
[музыка]
will go just reasonable, it can already go in a
пойдет как раз разумным уже может идет
reasonable way that you don’t need to invent a
разумно путем что не нужно изобретать
bunch of papers, but
кучу бумаг разрешение а
you need to urgently if we want to keep up, so to speak,
нужно срочно если мы хотим так сказать
then
то
give scientists faster  we’ll work some kind of
быстрее ученым давать какую-то
green light inventor
изобретателем зеленый свет работать
now, by the
сейчас
way, the station, but really,
будем ошо кстати станции но реально если
if it’s a hoax for us and
нас это обман и просто
I just don’t know about reality, I’m sad, I
я не знаю насчет реальность я грущу я
didn’t talk and between the prices there
не разговаривал и между цены там
went up, something disappeared from the counter for
подорожали пропала что-то с прилавка
miles, these are fakes,
миль это фейки
I can calmly the
я могу спокойно
prices went up
цены поднялись
I’ll be honest, I’m not amazed at the prices, I’m buying, let’s say I have
честно скажу не поражен покупаю допустим
sneakers,
у
too, and will ask why  auk it's
меня тоже так и спросит почему паук это
dude why you ridge why us
чувак а почему вас хребет а почему нас
bread i
хлеб я
don't think
не задумываюсь
i'm family .
я семейный .
and
а
here I
вот у
have it mathematically, but incomparably,
меня математически носим но несравненно
but look, how do you, for example,
а вот смотрите а как у вас например у
have a bunch of national republics in Russia,
вас в россии там куча национальных
so there is
республик так есть
Tatarstan there, Chechnya,
татарстан там чечня
Bashkortostan, and you go further, so they don’t have
башкортостан и ты дальше так у них нет
such a desire to secede either, how the USSR
такого желания тоже отделиться как ссср
collapsed that they want there too
распался что вот они хотят там тоже
they didn’t hear, added all against the background of these
не слышали добавил весь на фоне этих там
warriors there, so further, too, I didn’t
воины так дальше тоже не
get that, but how do you feel
данного получал которых а как вы
about coding personally, it’s
относитесь к кодируют лично будешь он
as if he’s specific to read
как будто специфический читать
in general
по общему что
what to say, but
как бы сказать а
can
может смотреть
look, look, here was Lenin, Lenin died
вот смотрите вот был ленин ленин умер
instead of him, Stalin became from  Georgia then
вместо него стал сталин из грузии то
loads, but you are considering this
грузит а вот вы рассматриваете такой
option
вариант
Putin will die and Kadyrov will become instead of him
путин умрет и вместо него станет кадыров
and will be like Stalin and why not
и будет как сталин а почему не бы
because
потому что
I think Kadyrov has no such experience
я думаю кадырова нет такого опыта
and who has if Putin died
а у кого есть вот если если путин умер
from whom who has experience
от кого у кого есть опыт
you what if  Putin will die, all of Russia will
ты что если путин умрет вся россия
fall apart in it whoever has no experience, I don’t
развалится в ней у кого нет опыта я не
know, but I can’t
знаю но я не могу сказать
naturally say all these people who
естественно вот этих всех которые на
debated the
дебатировали
channel
канал
among this
среди этих вот
here it turns out that such a huge
здесь получается что такая огромная
country with nuclear potential rests on
страна с ядерным потенциалом держится на
one grandfather, that is, grandfather dies and
одном дедушки то есть дедушка умирает и
everything has
все
risen completely, and what he deserved,
поднялся вполне а чем он заслужил
well, look, it doesn’t seem to you that,
ну а смотрите вот вам не кажется что
for example, the money that was allocated
например те деньги которые выделялись
all the time for the army is not for you in the city of a
все время на армию вот не вам в городе
hospital  they built there only she army
больницу построили там лишь она армия их
plundered them so ukraine was able to
разворовывали вот украина смогла
sink some super cruiser yours
потопить какой-то супер крейсер ваши вот
this moscow
этот москва
750 million dollars is
750 миллионов долларов
still
еще
here
здесь
and
и
because you don’t want
потому что не охота
to live without news yourself yes today
на живете без новостей себе да сегодня
everything is fine thank you for talking all
хорошо все спасибо вам за разговор все